# ANKUSH VARSHNEYA

ankushvarshneya@outlook.com ankushvarshneya.azurewebsites.net 4 Stoneleigh St, Ottawa, ON K2G 7A2 (613) 823-2635

ca.linkedin.com/in/AnkushVarshneya https://github.com/AnkushVarshneya/

## AVAILABILITY AND SUMMARY

I am an enthusiastic developer and a graduating student with 2 years of experience looking for a full time or internship position. I have a desire to constantly be challenged and learn. I like working on both front-end and back-end of a product to have a better view of everything, however my interests lie in databases/BI/mining, network computing and web development.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Computer Science Network Computing Stream, Statistics Minor (Co-op) Carleton University - Ottawa, Ontario.

**September 2011 - Present** 

- Major: 10.56/12.00 (88.00%) / Minor: 10.12/12.00 (84.33%) / CGPA: 10.06/12 (83.83%)
- Renewable Entrance Scholarship 2011, 2012
- Anticipated Graduation Date: Fall 2016

## **SKILLS**

• Languages: SQL(PL/Embedded/JDBC), Java, .NET Visual Basics, .Net C#, C, C++, Scheme, Prolog, SAS

• Frameworks: DataTable.js, ASP.NET MVC Framework, Entity framework, Hibernate framework, JPA, Ext GWT

• Web: HTML5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, WordPress, PHP

• Tools: VIM, GIT, Subversion, JIRA, TFS, LaTeX, SSH, GDB, GCC, G++, Valgrind, Visual Studio, Eclipse,

Embarcadero, LDAP, IIS/Apache, System commands/calls in Linux, Bash Scripts, Balsamiq Mockups

• Others: UML, Agile Software Design and Development, Object Oriented Design, User Interphase design

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Programmer / Analyst** 

Office of the Auditor General of Canada (OAG)
Ottawa, Ontario

May 2014 – August 2014 January 2015 – August 2015

• Develop and designed maintenance related functionality inside a .NET based web application using the .NET MVC and Entity frameworks with a combination of HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, JavaScript/JQuery, Bootstrap and the Data Tables plugins; allowing admins to maintain data within the web application eliminating the use of 3<sup>rd</sup> party solution for maintenance

- Refactored pre-existing code base and carried out tests cases to determine software defect resulting in a bug free product
- Used Embarcadero to help model and create schema of an application to allow it to store data effectively
- Created API's within an application to allow front-end developers to effectively create the user interphase
- Updated the database using SQL and performed maintenance related tasks on other products to allow for accurate data
- Implemented an engine to automate emails to users based on an event in the application using SMTP protocol

## Java Developer and Designer

Nakina Systems – Network Integrity

**May 2013 – December 2013** 

Kanata, Ontario

- Revamped the legacy logging component of a J2EE based Network Operating System (NOS) to be more current
- Solved software and performance related defects within NOS by restructuring the logging system, among other things, from the back-end in order to make the data more organized and generalized, as well as developing upon existing EJBs and APIs in back-end / front-end code, hence eliminating overhead code, making the application more efficient
- Implemented SQL amenders to translate existing log to new log structure making upgrades on systems more manageable
- Implemented Common Event Format (CEF) logs via syslog support on top of the logging component using syslog4j and log4j in order to provide users the ability to use 3<sup>rd</sup> party logging solutions to view logs generated by the app in real time
- Co-implemented dependency free version of a product for internal use to help developers easily test and develop upon
- Worked with Hibernate framework and Java Persistence API and optimized various back-end codes to allow for major
  performance gains while creating, importing, cloning, and accessing large sets of bulk data with a template credential
  application within NOS to address the clients concern over performance

## Web Developer/IT Personnel

#### **National Research Council of Canada (NRC)**

May 2012 - August 2012

Ottawa, Ontario

- Developed a web application using a IIS, MSSQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript solution, to allow users to enter resource/facility usage data electronically and automatically generate reports / invoices as needed from any computer, based on requirements gathered from business users through regular consultations; hence providing an intuitive solution to the clients liking which eliminated the previously used paper based approach allowing for greater level of productivity
- Secured web application by integrating LDAP for authentication allowing administrators to better track users
- Gained IT experience by assisting IT Personnel with minor tasks to accomplish them in a timely and organized fashion

Cashier/Server Tim Horton's June 2008 - October 2010

Ottawa, Ontario

- Provided efficient and comprehensive customer service at the restaurant by taking and making the orders from customers, collecting and handling cash, and answering customer queries resulting in a positive customer satisfaction
- Collaborated with team members by multitasking in different activities in the restaurant and organizing and cleaning up the restaurant allowing for a positive atmosphere in the restaurant leading to a pleasant experience for the customer

# Register/Technician/

## Chinmaya Mission Ottawa (Volunteer)

**July 2007 – August 2007** 

**Activity Director's Assistant** 

Ottawa, Ontario

- Registered children by gathering appropriate paper work and fees hence increasing efficiency of the administrative staff
- Helped get equipment ready when needed allowing for a smooth experience for the attendees and organizers of the events
- Helped organize rooms and supervised children during the activities leading to a fun experience for the children and a stress-free experience for the Activity Director

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Tor-Messager (COMP 3203 Group Project)**

https://github.com/AnkushVarshneya/Tor-messaging

- A proof of concept tor messaging app built using Tor and Java
- My contributions were made to the UI and the sending functionality of the messages

# **CUTPS-system (COMP 3004 Group Project)**

https://github.com/AnkushVarshneya/cutps-system

- A Textbook Publishing System which allowed users to buy and sell books and was built using C++, QT, SQL
- My contribution were to the database access layer/backend/database modeling, design documentation, and parts of the UI

### **CUTEAS (COMP 2404 Group Project)**

https://github.com/AnkushVarshneya/CUTEAS

- A TA management system which allows professors to assign TA's to courses and was built using C++ and GLIB
- My contribution were to the code used for saving and retrieving data from flat files as well as parts of the UI.

#### **DB-Programming**

https://github.com/AnkushVarshneya/DB-Programming

Various samplers on SQL related Technologies

WordPress Website

https://github.com/AnkushVarshneya/wordpress-theme

# **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

In my spare time I like following various tech magazines such as IDG news service, Mobile Nation and many more to keep up with the latest tech trends. I also like exploring current technologies as well and looking at some historic technologies to try and broaden my knowledge as well as to feed my curiosity of what's out there. Additionally, I enjoy assembling and playing around with computer hardware as well as computer software. In contrast, I have done various art projects in the graphics and visual arts and enjoy bringing in that kind of creativity into projects related to my field. Lastly, I like exploring about my Indian heritage, culture and native language, Hindi, by reading through various religious texts and following Indian TV shows and films as well as interacting with members of the local Indian community here in Ottawa.

# **REFERENCES**

References, letter of recommendation, past work evaluations, transcript available at ankushvarshneya.azurewebsites.net.